The discussions he started became of great interest and the approach was always the same.
Anyone who believed to know the answer was challenged
And Socrates submitted the answer a review by asking a number of follow -up questions.
Almost always emerged the shortcomings in the original response
Then the interlocutor revised the reasoning and tried again.
Socratic thinking became famous and it revealed ignorance in people with alleged knowledge.
Although Socrates herself rarely gave any final answers (and in that case it would have been included in his method
To emphasize that each such response would also be subjected to review) he stimulated an interest in philosophy.
He taught people to question everything, which would also be his ruin.
In the end, he was arrested by the authorities who are tired of being constantly being questioned,
And he was sentenced to death.
Although his friends and students offered help in fleeing, Socrates opposed this
And talked about how citizens must obey the laws and the authorities' decisions.
After saying goodbye to his wife and children he spoke with his disciples about the immortality of the soul
and then emptied the poison cup as a soldier full of excuses gave him.
There are lots of rumors and claims about Socrates,
Among other things, he is said to have been small, thick and unusually ugly.
According to information he was married to Xantippa - a very quarrelsome and angry woman,
But also the only one who could defeat Socrates in a discussion.
He is alleged to have also been virtually insensitive to cold and physical exertion,
And it is said that he could stand pondering for hours, completely unaware of the outside world.
Often he spoke to his inner voice, his "daimon", when he doubted that a way to act really the right thing.
A major problem when it comes to our knowledge of Socrates is that he never wrote anything.
Most of what we know about him comes from his students, mainly Plato.
But what is really reproduced by Socrates thoughts in these writings
And what in turn is Plato's own doctrine is something that is constantly being discussed.
In summary, Socrates has had a huge influence on philosophy.
Not only did he define many of the issues that philosophy is still engaged in today, such as moral philosophy,
His dialectical method and emphasis on critical thinking have permeated philosophy since the days of ancient times.